# Stephen Price



inquire.stelloprint@protonmail.com



linkedin.com/in/slprice



https://stephenlprice.github.io/portfolio/

### **Summary**

I have 3+ years of experience as a Solutions Consultant in data visualization and API design (OpenAPI). Throughout this time I have pursued opportunities for personal development in web development. I decided to pursue software development full time and I am now attending the Coding Boot Camp at University of Texas ending on March 2021.

I have always been product expert and I am used to collaborating with developers, product managers and software architects. I am a confident presenter and teacher that can explain complicated concepts to obtain actionable results. Communication is essential for any project, especially when they require team-work and problem solving.

I have a strong understanding of Javascript, HTML and CSS (including frameworks or tools such as Bootstrap, jQuery and Materialize). I am also proficient with Python for data analysis and as a backend (Django & the Wagtail CMS). I am comfortable using R and Docker as well. I am currently expanding my knowledge into Node, Express, MongoDB and MySQL. Additionally I am proficient using Tableau for data visualization, Stoplight for API design & documentation, Spectral for OpenAPI linting & validation and Prism for API mocking & contract testing.

My portfolio contains work I have been developing over the years and it is available here: https://stephenlprice.github.io/portfolio/

You can find me on Github: https://github.com/stephenlprice

## **Experience**



#### **Solutions Consultant**

#### Stoplight

Dec 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 1 month)

- · Supported the global sales team.
- Customers were mostly developers, software architects and product managers.
- Enable end-users in the use of Stoplight Studio for API design under the OpenAPI specification as well as management of their Stoplight Workspace (API portal & design environment).
- Supported on-premise POCs deployed via Docker.
- Shared customer feedback with Stoplight's Product Team and monitored company repositories for insights into product and roadmap updates.
- Learned to use additional Stoplight tools such as Spectral for OAS linting/validation and Prism for API mocking & contract testing.

#### Senior Product Consultant

#### Tableau Software

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019 (1 year)

• Presales engineer supporting inside sales teams covering Latin America, the Caribbean, the United States and Canada.

- Confident presenter and thorough student I believe that industry and product knowledge combined with sales strategy and a positive attitude lead to the consistent attainment of company objectives.
- Consistency, curiosity and self-reliance are the main factors behind being a top sales performer and subject matter expert.
- Product expert in the Tableau platform composed of applications for data visualization, data preparation, cloud based and on premise secure hosting as well as integrations in areas such as authentication, statistical analysis, data source connectivity, cloud-hosting platforms and Salesforce.
- Strong technical knowledge in data visualization and analysis, front-end web development (JavaScript, CSS, HTML). Confident in back-end development (Python/Django), Amazon Web Services, Python and R for data analysis, server architecture and web services. Familiar with Docker containerization, Azure, Google Cloud Platform and databases (MySQL).

#### Product Consultant

Tableau Software

Jul 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 6 months)

#### Marketing Coordinator & Contract Administrator

HILONG GROUP OF COMPANIES

Jul 2014 - Mar 2017 (2 years 9 months)

- In charge of 4 "Just in Time" steel pipe supply chain contracts for drilling and completion of oil wells operated by state owned and multinational corporations up to a value of USD 40 million.
- Proven track record of more than 170+ successful deliveries of steel pipe under DDP terms at the wellsite without registering a single delay, thus resulting in operational reliability and costs savings for our clients as well as avoiding hefty contractual fines.
- Responsible for tender processes with state owned and multinational corporations for the provision of steel pipe and drilling services (drilling and workover rigs).
- Development of a system for managing the tubular supply chain based on the drilling and completion programs of the company's clients, which was then used by their engineers to plan for future consumption in an increasingly risky investment environment.
- Responsible for the successful evaluation of our logistics center and business segment carried out by Petroamazonas EP under the API Q2 standard.

#### **Acting General Manager**

HILONG GROUP OF COMPANIES

Mar 2015 - Oct 2015 (8 months)

Trusted by the company to found the Peruvian branch of Hilong Group's oil service and engineering business line for the development of OCTG and oil field accessory business opportunities.

## Spanish Instructor

Atlanta International Language Institute, LLC

Mar 2014 - Jul 2014 (5 months)

• Teach Spanish language skills, culture and history to students in group or private lessons that take place in either offsite or classroom settings

## Teaching Assistant

Alma College

Sep 2012 - Apr 2013 (8 months)

• Provided teaching assistance in the Spanish Language Department

#### Commercial Assistant

S3 Superior Support Services

Oct 2011 - Dec 2011 (3 months)

- Worked with an international logistics company importing equipment, parts and products related to the oil industry from exploration to production specifically drilling fluid recycling units, as well as other importable items
- Applied skills involved with importation such as Incoterms, calculated transportation costs, taxes, delivery time, quoted products and devised suitable prices for clients

#### **Education**

## The University of Texas at Austin

Coding Boot Camp, Full Stack Web Development

2020 - 2021

Full-time, intensive coding boot camp at University of Texas in collaboration with Trilogy Education.

## Alma College

Bachelor of Arts (BBA), Business Administration 2009 - 2013

## Hutong School

Certificate Intermediate Sufficiency, Mandarin Chinese

Studied in the intensive Mandarin Chinese program at the Hutong School, spending two months in Beijing and one month at Shanghai.

#### Skills

JavaScript • Python (Programming Language) • Django • Web Development • Front-end Development • Analytical Skills • Tableau • R • SQL • Wagtail CMS